A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), Office Files of Anthony D. Romero FA591
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), Office Files of Anthony D. Romero
1993-2001
Rockefeller Archive Center
Romero, Anthony D.
Ford Foundation
FA591
1.31 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Contains correspondence and subject files.
Biographical / Historical
Anthony D. Romero is a lawyer, civil rights advocate, and nonprofit executive. He worked at the Ford Foundation from 1992 to 2001 and became Director of the Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ) Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC) unit in 1996. In 2001, Romero was appointed Executive Director of the American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU). He is the first Latino and openly gay man in that position.
Romero joined the Ford Foundation in 1992 as a Program Officer in the Rights and Social Justice Program (RSJ). He was appointed as Director of the newly created PSJ HRIC unit after the Foundation's program reorganization in 1996.
Prior to joining the Ford Foundation, Romero worked at the Rockefeller Foundation. He graduated from Princeton University's Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affairs with a B.A. in international affairs in 1987 and earned a J.D. from Stanford Law School in 1990.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series by file type.
Collection arrangement is as follows: Series I. Chronological Correspondence, 1998-2000 Series II. Subject Files, 1993-2001
- Chronological Correspondence, 1998-2000; I
  - Alphabetical Chrons, 1998 January-November (Box 1)
  - External Mail Chrons, 1999 January (Box 1)
  - Internal Mail Chrons, 1999 January (Box 1)
  - External Mail Chrons, 2000 January (Box 1)
  - Internal Mail Chrons, 2000 January (Box 1)
- Subject Files, 1993-2001; II
  - Affirmative Action, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
  - Capacity Building, 1998-2000 (Box 1)
  - Reports, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - Southern Regional Council, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
  - Transitional Justice Meeting, 2000 April 6 (Box 1)